BILL GARDNER

WEB APPLICATIONS DEVELOPER

As an analytical thinker and a critical and creative problem solver, I am able to call on more than 15 years of engineering and product development experience to solve complex software development questions. In addition to being experienced in Wordpress development, I also develop object oriented web applications in Python and PHP. I am seeking opportunities that will allow me to contribute my skills to the development of elegant software products as well as allowing my continued growth as a software developer.

Contact:

(443) 340-5272 phone:

bill@williamjgardner.com email: www.williamjgardner.com portfolio: github.com/williamjohngardner github: linkedin.com/in/williamjohngardner

Education:

linkedin:

Python & Django Curriculum

The Iron Yard May - August 2016

B.S Industrial Design

Virginia Tech May 2000, Cum Laude

Technical Skills:

Python Django PHP Wordpress HTML/CSS lava Java Script Git Bootstrap MySQL PostgreSQL Heroku

Object Oriented Programming **Functional Programming**

Photoshop Illustrator Acrobat InDesign Rhino3D Solidworks AutoCAD Google Sketchup

Work Experience:

EverConvert

Senior Web Developer, 2017 - Present

Responsible for managing development team of both full time employees and freelance developers to meet production schedule and new product development schedule. Oversaw successful deployment of 30+ client websites in 2017.

Web Developer, 2016 - 2017

Responsible for development of PHP based Wordpress themes and websites for an SEO marketing firm providing services to the law office industry.

Freelance Web Developer

2011 - Present

Development of Wordpress websites for non-profits and small businesses.

William John Gardner Design Studio, LLC

Principal, 2011 - 2016

Owner of a studio specializing in custom furniture design for interior designers

Niermann Weeks

Design Development Manager, 2007 - 2010

Oversaw & implemented a new 3D CAD system that shortened the product development lifecycle from 18 to 2 weeks, an increase of over 4600% from the previous 4 years combined.

Alstom Transportation

Senior Field Service Engineer, 2007

Led the onsite installation & commissioning of the door system for the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority 2000/3000 series & 6000 series trains.

BMK Architects, PC

Associate Designer, 2005 - 2007

Prepared construction documentation for all client projects as well as implemented a 3D rendering workflow that allowed the architects to more quickly communicate design intents and design changes to their clients.

IFE North America, Inc.

Project Engineer, 2001 - 2005

Oversaw implementation, field service, and training of door systems for rail cars and subways in the North American market.